

# EDWINA BADDOO

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

AN ENTHUSIASTIC SALES AND GUEST RELATIONS EXECUTIVE WITH 3 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE IN THE HOSPITALITY INDUSTRY, GAINING VALUABLE SKILLS IN RELATIONSHIP BUILDING, STRATEGIC PLANNING, MARKETING, AND PROJECT MANAGEMENT. STRONG TRACK RECORD OF QUICKLY LEARNING AND ADAPTING TO NEW AND COMPLEX SITUATIONS. EAGER TO LEVERAGE A DIVERSE RANGE OF TALENTS IN AN ENGAGING PROFESSIONAL SETTING. COMMITTED TO LIFELONG LEARNING, PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT, AND CREATING, DEVELOPING, AND MAINTAINING POSITIVE CUSTOMER SERVICE AND EXPERIENCES TO INCREASE SALES THROUGH CREATIVE COMMUNICATION. FLEXIBLE, HAVE GOOD ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS AS WELL AS GREAT INTERPERSONAL SKILLS..

## **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- CREATIVE PROBLEM SOLVING
- FLEXIBILITY IN SITUATIONS
- Guest service-oriented
- Technological savvy (MS Office, Ezee Hotel software e.t.c)
- Self-motivated and driven by targets
- Positive Mindset

# **CONTACT INFORMATION:**

TELEPHONE: +233243078576

EMAIL:

EDWINA.BADDOO@CESARRITZCOLLEGES.C

LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/EDWINA-BADDOO-418A408B



# **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

#### **CESAR RITZ COLLEGES**

MA IN INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS IN HOTEL & TOURISM MANAGEMENT
ENGLISCH GRUSS-STRASSE 43, CH-3902 BRIG, SWITZER LAND 2017 - APRIL 2019

## **EUROPEAN SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS**

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT

APRIL 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

4 MANDEVILLE PL, MARYLEBONE, LONDON W1U 2BG, UK

#### ASHESI UNIVERSITY

BSC MANAGEMENT INFORMATIONS SYSTEMS
BEREKUSO, GREATER ACCRA, GHANA

AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2016



## **CAREER HISTORY**

## PEDUASE VALLEY RESORT

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

November 2020 - September 2021

- Prepared sales-related documents and presentations which included reports proposals, contracts, banquet event orders, competitor analysis and international and local market trends.
- EFFECTIVELY DEVELOPED CONTENT TO PROMOTE AND INCREASE AWARENESS OF THE P.V.R BRAND IMAGE BOTH INTERNALLY AND EXTERNALLY. GATHERED MATERIALS AND ASSEMBLED INFORMATION PACKAGES SUCH AS BROCHURES, POSTERS AND OTHER PROMOTIONAL MATERIALS.
- SUCCESSFULLY PLANNED AND EXECUTED 12 IN-HOUSE PROGRAMMED EVENTS WHICH INCLUDED EVENTS FOR CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR ACTIVITIES. VALENTINE'S DAY EVENT, EASTER ACTIVITIES FIG.
- PROFITABLY DEVELOPED, PRICED AND SUCCESSFULLY IMPLEMENTED 6 PRODUCTS AND
  PACKAGES SUCH BIRTHDAY AND ANNIVERSARY PACKAGES WHICH CAN BE SOLD TO GUEST AS A
  CHANNEL TO GAIN REVENUE
- SUCCESSFULLY ESTABLISHED, RETAINED AND EXPANDED PARTNERSHIPS WITH KEY MEDIA INSTITUTIONS AND VENDORS IN GHANA AND NEGOTIATED 5 COMPLEX CONTRACTS WITH NEW CLIENTS AND CLOSED 3 SHORT-TERM AGREEMENTS TO INCREASE SALES.

### JOE BAAZE ENTERPRISE

SALES AND ACCOUNTING ASSOCIATE

APRIL 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

- DAILY CHECKING OF CASH ACCOUNTS.
- -CALCULATING AND ASSISTING CUSTOMER PAYMENTS.
- -Working in a fast-paced environment and under pressure excellently.
- -ASSISTING CUSTOMERS BY PROVIDING INFORMATION AND RESOLVING PROBLEMS.
- -ASSISTING WITH DUTIES SUCH AS INVENTORY MANAGEMENT AND BOOKKEEPING.

## RELAIS & CHATEAUX IL BOTTACCIO LUXURY HOTEL

CROSS DEPARTMENTAL INTERN

AUGUST 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

- SIMPLE KITCHEN TASKS: PEELING, STORING, CLEANING, PREPARING MEALS
- LEARNING AND PRESENTING ARTS OF DISH PRESENTATION.
- Managing and controlling Inventory.
- Supervising and assisting in housekeeping duties
- SUPERVISING AND HELPING WITH FRONT OFFICE DUTIES SUCH AS WELCOMING AND ASSISTING GUESTS CHECK-IN AND CHECK-OUT.

#### GROUPE NDOUM

Human Resourse Assistant

NOVERMBER 2016 - JUNE 2017

- Update our internal databases with new employee information, including contact details and employment forms
- SCREEN RESUMES AND APPLICATION FORMS
- SCHEDULE AND CONFIRM INTERVIEWS WITH CANDIDATES
- PREPARE HR-RELATED REPORTS AS NEEDED
- PARTICIPATE IN ORGANIZING COMPANY EVENTS AND CAREERS DAYS



#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

- -ENGLISH (MOTHER TONGUE)
- FRENCH (BASIC)